Robert H. Kokernot papers FA1407
Rockefeller Archive Center
Robert H. Kokernot papers
1955-1975
Rockefeller Archive Center
Kokernot, Robert H.
FA1407
3.24 Cubic Feet
- Robert H. Kokernot Films, c.1950s-1970s; 1
  Arrangement
  Films remain in Robert H. Kokernot's original order.
  Conditions Governing Access
  When requesting to view audiovisual material, please refer to the Title and the AV Number (example: AV 1916).
  Researchers are asked to check the "Restrictions" note for each Title. If a Title does not currently have an access copy, please contact a RAC archivist for further instruction.
  All inquiries to view film prints require advanced notice of at least 2 business days, and may necessitate notice of up to one week. Individual items, including those that are not available in modern formats, may be restricted from access at the discretion of RAC.
  Scope and Contents
  Films documenting Robert H. Kokernot's scientific work in Africa for the Rockefeller Foundation.
  - Africa Films, c.1950s-1970s; 1
    - Kokernot Film 1, 1957 July 11 - August 23; Silent, Color, 16 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 2465)
      Access copy available.
      Scenes in Mozambique
    - Kokernot Film 2, 1957 August 6-9; Silent, Color, 17 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 2466)
      Mueda and Mocimboa do Rovuma
    - Kokernot Film 3, 1957 August 4; 1959 March 22; Silent, Color, 17 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 2467)
      Island of Mozambique, Cabaceria
    - Kokernot Film 4, 1959 March-April; 1960 March; Silent, Color, 20 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 2468)
      Lumbo
    - Kokernot Film 5, 1959 March 13; 1957 August 12; Silent, Color, 29 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 2469)
      Initiating Field Work at Lumbo, Trip to the Island of Ibo
    - Kokernot Film 6, c.1950s-1960s; Silent, Color, 17 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 2470)
      Tongaland
    - Kokernot Film 7, c.1950s-1960s; Silent, Color, 18 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 2471)
      Painting Face (Mozambique), Fixing Hair and Preparation of Sugar Cane Drink, Collecting Bulbs and Kraal Scenes
    - Kokernot Film 8, 1960 May 27 - June 23; Silent, Color, 18 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 2472)
      Sa da Banderia, Buco Zau
    - Kokernot Film 9, 1960 May 27 - June 23; Silent, Color, 17 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 2473)
      Nova Lisboa
    - Kokernot Film 10, 1959 May 28 - June 10; Silent, Color, 19 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 2474)
      Eastern Caprivi Strip and Mababe Depression
    - Kokernot Film 11, 1959 May - June; Silent, Color, 18 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 2475)
      Okavango Swamp and Caprivi Strip
    - Kokernot Film 12, 1959 June; Silent, Color, 18 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 2476)
      Sleeping Sickness in the Caprivi Strip and at Maun, Bechuanaland
    - Kokernot Film 13, 1959 June; Silent, Color, 20 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 2477)
      Hottentots
    - Kokernot Film 14, 1959 June 28; Silent, Color, 18 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 2478)
      Bushmen - Lone Tree, Obtaining Blood Specimens and General Scenes
    - Kokernot Film 15, 1959 June 28; Silent, Color, 19 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 2479)
      Bushmen - Lone Tree: Skinning Springbok and General Views of Shelter for Sleeping and of the People
    - Kokernot Film 16, 1955 June 11-19; Silent, Color, 16 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 2480)
      En Route to Victoria Falls
    - Kokernot Film 17, 1955 June 11-19; Silent, Color, 16 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 2481)
      At Victoria Falls
    - Kokernot Film 19, 1960 May; Silent, Color, 13 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 2482)
      Kruger National Park - Nwanedzi Camp and Olifants
    - Kokernot Film 20, c.1960; Silent, Color, 18 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 2483)
      Kruger National Park - Elephants Watering in River Camp at Shingwidzi
    - Kokernot Film 21, c.1960; Silent, Color, 17 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 2484)
      Kruger National Park - Lunch on Hill Near Shigomane Look-Out Tower, Camp at Punda Milia and a Variety of Animals
    - Kokernot Film 22, c.1960; Silent, Color, 9 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 2485)
      Black Herons Feeding at Simbu Pan Kruger National Park - Elephant at Parfuri, Lion (Changing of the Guard), Baobab Trees
    - Kokernot Film 23, 1957 July 25-26; Silent, Color, 17 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 2486)
      Hluhluwe and Gorongosa Game Reserves
    - Kokernot Film 24, 1957 July 17-18; Silent, Color, 9 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 2487)
      Chopi Dancers at Zandamela, Mozambique
    - Kokernot Film 25, 1957 July 21; Silent, Color, 9 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 2488)
      Ruins Near Vilanculos, Mozambique - Khami Ruins Near Bulawayo - Zimbabwe Near Fort Victoria
    - Kokernot Film 26, c.1955; Silent, Color, 19 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 2489)
      Field Work - Mosquitoes, Monkeys, and Small Mammals
    - Kokernot Film 27, c.1955; Silent, Color, 18 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 2490)
      Field Work - Birds, People, Cattle, and Taking Specimens to Inhambane
    - Kokernot Film 28, c.1950s-1960s; Silent, Color, 18 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 2491)
      Laboratory Work - Serologic Tests (HAI, CF), Processing Mosquitoes, (NT), Response in Mice to Inoculation with Arboviruses, Mosquito Feeding
    - Kokernot Film 29, 1974 December 20-29; Silent, Color, 18 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 2492)
      Lisbon, Tzaneen, Kruger National Park
    - Kokernot Film 30, 1974 December 28 - 1975 January 6; Silent, Color, 19 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 2493)
      Kruger National Park, Near Pietermaritzburg, Hluhluwe Game Reserve, Ndum
    - Kokernot Film 31, 1975 January 5-24; Silent, Color, 18 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 2494)
      Durban, Umhlanga Rocks, Oudtshoorn, Cape Town and Camps Bay, Victoria Falls, Egypt
    - Kokernot Film 32, 1962-1963; Silent, Color, 20 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 2495)
      Rio Raposo Field Station
    - Kokernot Film 33, 1962-1963; Silent, Color, 17 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 2496)
      Purace, Indian Market at Silvia, Jurado, Magdalena River
    - Kokernot Film 34A, 1962; Silent, Color, 10 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 2497)
      Cartagena, Rio Raposa Field Station
    - Kokernot Film 34B, 1962; Silent, Color, 11 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 2498)
    - Kokernot Film 35, 1962; Silent, Color, 21 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 2499)
      Cali and Environs - Garden, Guy Hayes New House, Picnic, Country Home, Bullfight
    - Kokernot Film 36, 1962-1963; Silent, Color, 21 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 2500)
      Cali and Environs - Garden, Christmas, Birthdays, Picnic
    - Kokernot Film 37, 1963 April; Silent, Color, 16 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 2501)
      Pasto and Laguna de La Cocha
    - Kokernot Film 38, 1963 June 18-19; 1963 April; Silent, Color, 17 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 2502)
      Rio Raposa and Popayan
    - Kokernot Film 39, 1962 August 28-September 2; Silent, Color, 20 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 2503)
      Llanos and Amazons
    - Kokernot Film 40, 1962 November -December; Silent, Color, 12 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 2504)
      Guajira Peninsula - Man on Horse, Corn Gruel, Law Enforcement Man, Young Goat, Grinding Corn, Mosqito Collecting, Boys Face and Body Painting, Stew Cooking, House Building at Manaure, and Dance
    - Kokernot Film 41, 1962 November -December; Silent, Color, 19 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 2505)
      Guajira Peninsula - Thorn Bush Vegetation, Flamingos, Donkey, Washing Clothes, Dancing, Blanket Weaving, and Milking